https://www.pittimmagine.com/it/pittimmagine/corporate/privacy

BUYER INFORMATION NOTICE
EXHIBITOR INFORMATION NOTICE
PRESS INFORMATION NOTICE
Privacy policy:
guarantee of data protection and confidentiality
Information notice concerning protection of personal data pursuant to art. 12 and following EU regulation 679/2016
BUYER INFORMATION NOTICE
Pursuant to the new Regulation 679/2016, in accordance with the principle of accountability, any processing of personal data shall be lawful, fair and transparent. Specifically, this means that processing will be done in respect of the principles of lawfulness, fairness, correctness, proportionality, necessity, accuracy, completeness and security, and that the Data Subject is advised of the existence of the processing, its purposes and the rights which the Data Subject can exercise.
With this in mind, we provide below the necessary information regarding the processing that we normally carry out and the rights you have under current privacy legislation.
In general, we do not carry out processing of any particular relevance with specific regard to natural persons. We do not collect a lot of data and what we do collect is restricted to personal details, company names, email addresses or telephone numbers, or, essentially, that data needed to fulfil contractual obligations and connected to the legal obligations incumbent on our company, or that data which we process on the basis of our legitimate interests in carrying out our business in compliance with practices in the sector in which we operate and in proportion to that which is normally expected within the scope of professionalism.
When necessary, as part of carrying out an Event or an initiative connected to one, we may provide you with additional information in relation to any further processing which may be done, which is understood as being supplementary to or even just a specification of this information notice.
We invite you to read this information carefully and we remain available should you have any queries or require further information regarding how we process and how we safeguard your personal data.
Information notice concerning the protection of personal data pursuant to article 12 et seq. of EU regulation 679/2016
CONTROLLER - CONTACT DETAILS
PITTI IMMAGINE S.r.l., with offices in Via Faenza, 111 – Florence, Italy, in the person of the legal representative pro-tempore, is the Controller in terms of processing personal data pursuant to and for the effects of EU Regulation 2016/679.
For any communication regarding privacy or to exercise a right due to a Data Subject under current legislation, the Controller has made this email address available: privacy@pittimmagine.com
CATEGORIES OF DATA – PROCESSING SYSTEMS
The personal data we process is that data requested on the paper form and/or by the computer registration system on the institutional site.
Generally speaking, we ask for personal details, company names, email addresses or telephone numbers.
The personal data provided on the registration form is also stored in a badge that we deliver to you in order to allow you to access the trade show.
By maintaining relationships with various companies, we will be able to collect information - personal and otherwise - relating to the company’s internal representatives (e.g. employees), such as contact details (email, telephone number, etc.), personal and tax details, company position, as well as other common personal data which is needed in order to fulfil contractual or professional dealings with the company. It should be noted that - in this regard - the company has the responsibility of divulging the contents of this information notice to company representatives whose data, for various reasons, is sent as part of the relationship with our company.
PROCESSING METHODS AND CONFIDENTIALITY OBLIGATION
Data is processed by means of IT tools and/or manually on paper, by persons expressly authorised by the Controller or, in any case, by persons bound by confidentiality agreements, using logic appropriate to the purposes for which the data was collected and, in any case, in order to guarantee the security and confidentiality of the data.
The data collected will not be disclosed or disseminated to third parties pursuant to the law.
THE PURPOSE OF THE PROCESSING - LEGAL BASIS
The personal data collected will be used for purposes connected with pre-contractual, contractual, legal, tax and accounting requirements, for service communications, to manage complaints and to provide information on our future trade show initiatives and events.
The personal data processed does not require your consent.
Indeed, processing the personal data collected is connected to pre-contractual and/or contractual issues, or is done to fulfil a specific legal obligation incumbent on the Controller, or is done to send information about services which are identical or similar to those you purchased when attending an event. In this latter case, the information activity is done on the basis of our legitimate interests in making you aware of our business and in promoting it amongst operators in the sector; within the limits of this purpose, and bearing in mind the professional relationship already established with you, we use the personal data, which you have provided us as part of the registration process in our system, to also send you our periodic Newsletter, without prejudice to your right to object to receiving the same, either from the outset or at any moment thereafter and without formality.
PROVIDING DATA
The data considered mandatory is that data needed to conclude a contract or to provide the requested services, or that data relating to the fulfilment of a specific legal obligation incumbent on the Controller (for example, the obligations related to keeping accounting and tax records). Failure to communicate this data will prevent a contract from being concluded or a service from being provided.
This data also meets one of the Controller’s legitimate interests which is to share this information with other companies in the "Centro di Firenze per la Moda Italiana" Group (of which Pitti Immagine S.r.l. is a part), due to organisational or coordination needs or to support the Controller’s activities, within the limits of necessity and proportionality regarding the purpose for which the data is sent, also taking into account the nature of the data processed and the relationship with the Data Subject.
TRANSFERRING DATA TO A THIRD COUNTRY
If data is transferred to a third country, the Controller will comply with the provisions of Chapter V of EU Regulation no. 679/2016. Every necessary precaution will be taken in order to ensure that the personal data is protected by basing this transfer on: a) adequacy decisions regarding third countries adopted by the European Commission; b) adequate guarantees given by the third party recipient pursuant to article 46 of the EU Regulation; c) adopting binding corporate rules.
The Controller will also transfer personal data, even in the absence of the aforementioned conditions, if one of the derogation situations exist as provided for by article 49 of the EU Regulation.
You may contact the Controller for more specific information on transfers made to a third country.
COMMUNICATION TO THIRD PARTIES
The data collected may be sent to third parties exclusively for the purposes specified above or to fulfil a connected, instrumental or supporting activity.
These third parties will process the data as independent Controllers or, depending on the case, as External Processors expressly appointed by the Controller. In this latter case, Processors will follow the Controller’s instructions and will be under the Controller’s supervision.
This essentially involves the following categories:
- the Controller's employees, suppliers and collaborators;
- external companies and other professionals who carry out specific services on our behalf;
- a service provider, to send the newsletter, which has been appointed as an external processor;
- bodies and Public Administrations for compliance with legal requirements;
The access badge which we deliver contains personal data that you provided us with in the registration form. Exhibitors are able to read this badge through an optical reader and this allows them access to the personal data contained in this form, in compliance with the purposes and the processing methods each one employs.
STORAGE TIMES
A Data Subject's personal data will be kept for the time necessary to fulfil the existing relationships between the parties and to fulfil the relative obligations, without prejudice to storing data for a longer period as may be required by law. Once such a period ends, the data will be erased.
THE DATA SUBJECT’S RIGHTS
In accordance with the law in force, the Data Subject may assert his/her rights vis-à-vis the Controller, as stated by Regulation 679/2016, i.e.:
- Right of access (art. 15);
- Right to rectification (art. 16);
- Right to erasure (art. 17);
- Right to restriction of processing (art. 18);
- Right to data portability (art. 20);
- Right to object (21);
- Right to withdraw consent;
- Right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority in the cases provided for by the Regulation. For more details, consult the Italian Data Protection Authority’s site www.garanteprivacy.it.
To exercise any of the aforementioned rights, the Controller should be contacted at the address indicated above, specifying the subject of the request.
Upon receiving a specific request from a Data Subject, pursuant to articles 15-22 of the Regulation, the Controller will provide as a response the information relating to the action taken without unjustified delay and, in any case, at the latest within one month from the date on which the request was received.
This deadline may be extended to two months, if necessary, after taking into account the complexity and number of requests received. The Controller will inform the Data Subject of any extension and the reasons for the delay within one month from the date on which the request was received.
In the event that the request is not deemed to be admissible, the Data Subject will be informed, without delay, and, at the latest, within one month from the date on which the request was received, of the reasons for which the request cannot be fulfilled and of the option to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority as well as the option of appealing to a judicial authority.
The Data Subject’s individual rights are detailed below:
RIGHT OF ACCESS – art. 15
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him/her is being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and the following information:
a) the purposes of the processing;
b) the categories of personal data concerned;
c) the recipients or categories of recipient to whom the personal data has been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;
d) where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;
e) the existence of the right to request from the Controller rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the Data Subject or to object to such processing;
f) the right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority;
g) where the personal data is not collected from the Data Subject, any available information as to its source;
h) the existence of automated decision-making processes, including profiling, referred to in article 22(1) and (4) and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for the Data Subject.
1. Where personal data is transferred to a third country or to an international organisation, the Data Subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards pursuant to article 46 relating to the transfer.
2. The Controller shall provide a copy of the personal data undergoing processing. For any further copies requested by the Data Subject, the Controller may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs. Where the Data Subject makes the request by electronic means, and unless otherwise requested by the Data Subject, the information shall be provided in a commonly used electronic form.
The right to obtain a copy shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO RECTIFICATION - art. 16
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him/her. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, the Data Subject shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
RIGHT TO ERASURE - art. 17
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him/her is being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and the following information:
a) the purposes of the processing;
b) the categories of personal data concerned;
c) the recipients or categories of recipient to whom the personal data has been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;
d) where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;
e) the existence of the right to request from the Controller rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the Data Subject or to object to such processing;
f) the right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority;
g) where the personal data is not collected from the Data Subject, any available information as to its source;
h) the existence of automated decision-making processes, including profiling, referred to in article 22(1) and (4) and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for the Data Subject.
1. Where personal data is transferred to a third country or to an international organisation, the Data Subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards pursuant to article 46 relating to the transfer.
2. The Controller shall provide a copy of the personal data undergoing processing. For any further copies requested by the Data Subject, the Controller may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs. Where the Data Subject makes the request by electronic means, and unless otherwise requested by the Data Subject, the information shall be provided in a commonly used electronic form.
The right to obtain a copy shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO RESTRICTION OF PROCESSING - art. 18
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies:
a) the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the Data Subject, for a period enabling the Controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data;
b) the processing is unlawful and the Data Subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests the restriction of their use instead;
c) the Controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but the data is required by the Data Subject to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law;
d) the Data Subject has objected to processing pursuant to article 21(1) pending the verification of whether the legitimate grounds of the Controller override those of the Data Subject.
2. Where processing has been restricted under paragraph 1, such personal data shall, with the exception of storage, only be processed with the Data Subject's consent or to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law or to protect the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest of the Union or of a Member State.
3. A Data Subject who has obtained restriction of processing pursuant to paragraph 1 shall be informed by the Controller before the restriction of processing is lifted.
RIGHT TO DATA PORTABILITY – art. 20
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to receive the personal data concerning him/her, which he/she has provided to a Controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and shall have the right to transmit that data to another controller without hindrance from the Controller to which the personal data has been provided, where:
a) the processing is based on consent pursuant to point (a) of article 6(1) or point (a) of article 9(2) or on a contract pursuant to point (b) of article 6(1); and
b) the processing is carried out by automated means.
2. In exercising his/her right to data portability pursuant to paragraph 1, the Data Subject shall have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible.
3. The exercise of the right referred to in paragraph 1 of this article shall be without prejudice to article 17. That right shall not apply to processing necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Controller.
4. The right referred to in paragraph 1 shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO OBJECT TO PROCESSING – art. 21
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to his/her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning him/her which is based on point (e) or (f) of article 6(1), including profiling based on those provisions. The Controller shall no longer process the personal data unless the Controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the Data Subject or to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law.
2. Where personal data is processed for direct marketing purposes, the Data Subject shall have the right to object at any time to the processing of the personal data concerning him/her for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.
3. Where the Data Subject objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the personal data shall no longer be processed for such purposes.
4. At the latest at the time of the first communication with the Data Subject, the right referred to in paragraphs 1 and 2 shall be explicitly brought to the attention of the Data Subject and shall be presented clearly and separately from any other information.
5. In the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, the Data Subject may exercise his/her right to object by automated means using technical specifications.
6. Where personal data is processed for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes pursuant to article 89(1), the Data Subject, on grounds relating to his/her particular situation, shall have the right to object to the processing of the personal data concerning him/her, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
NEWSLETTER SERVICE
If you do not wish to receive our newsletter, you may unsubscribe at any moment by clicking the "Unsubscribe" link found in any of the emails received from us.
In the event of a technical problem, you may notify us by email at the address given above.
EXHIBITOR INFORMATION NOTICE
Pursuant to the new Regulation 679/2016, in accordance with the principle of accountability, any processing of personal data shall be lawful, fair and transparent. Specifically, this means that processing will be done in respect of the principles of lawfulness, fairness, correctness, proportionality, necessity, accuracy, completeness and security, and that the Data Subject is advised of the existence of the processing, its purposes and the rights which the Data Subject can exercise.
With this in mind, we provide below the necessary information regarding the processing that we normally carry out and the rights you have under current privacy legislation.
In general, we do not carry out processing of any particular relevance with specific regard to natural persons. We do not collect a lot of data and what we do collect is restricted to personal details, company names, email addresses or telephone numbers, or, essentially, that data needed to fulfil contractual obligations and connected to the legal obligations incumbent on our company, or that data which we process on the basis of our legitimate interests in carrying out our business in compliance with practices in the sector in which we operate and in proportion to that which is normally expected within the scope of professionalism.
When necessary, as part of carrying out an Event or an initiative connected to one, we may provide you with additional information in relation to any further processing which may be done, which is understood as being supplementary to or even just a specification of this information notice.
We invite you to read this information carefully and we remain available should you have any queries or require further information regarding how we process and how we safeguard your personal data.
Information notice concerning the protection of personal data pursuant to article 12 et seq. of EU regulation 679/2016
CONTROLLER - CONTACT DETAILS
PITTI IMMAGINE S.r.l., with offices in Via Faenza, 111 – Florence, Italy, in the person of the legal representative pro-tempore, is the Controller in terms of processing personal data pursuant to and for the effects of EU Regulation 2016/679.
For any communication regarding privacy or to exercise a right due to a Data Subject under current legislation, the Controller has made this email address available: privacy@pittimmagine.com
CATEGORIES OF DATA – PROCESSING SYSTEMS
The personal data we process is that data requested on the paper form and/or by the “My Pitti” computer registration system on the institutional site.
Generally speaking, we ask for personal details, company names, email addresses or telephone numbers.
By maintaining relationships with various companies, we will be able to collect information - personal and otherwise - relating to the company’s internal representatives (e.g. employees) or its suppliers, such as contact details (email, telephone number, etc.), personal and tax details, company position, as well as other common personal data which is needed in order to fulfil contractual or professional dealings with the company. It should be noted that - in this regard - the company has the responsibility of divulging the contents of this information notice to company representatives and other parties whose data, for various reasons, is sent as part of the relationship with our company.
PROCESSING METHODS AND CONFIDENTIALITY OBLIGATION
Data is processed by means of IT tools and/or manually on paper, by persons expressly authorised by the Controller or, in any case, by persons bound by confidentiality agreements, using logic appropriate to the purposes for which the data was collected and, in any case, in order to guarantee the security and confidentiality of the data.
The data collected will not be disclosed or disseminated to third parties pursuant to the law.
THE PURPOSE OF THE PROCESSING - LEGAL BASIS
The personal data collected will be used for purposes connected with pre-contractual, contractual, legal, tax and accounting requirements, for service communications, to manage complaints and to provide information on our future trade show initiatives and events.
The personal data processed does not require your consent.
Indeed, processing the personal data collected is connected to pre-contractual and/or contractual issues, or is done to fulfil a specific legal obligation incumbent on the Controller, or is done to send information about services which are identical or similar to those you purchased when attending an event. In this latter case, the information activity is done on the basis of our legitimate interests in making you aware of our business and in promoting it amongst operators in the sector; within the limits of this purpose, and bearing in mind the professional relationship already established with you, we use the personal data, which you have provided us as part of the registration process in our system, to also send you our periodic Newsletter, without prejudice to your right to object to receiving the same, either from the outset or at any moment thereafter and without formality.
PROVIDING DATA
The data considered mandatory is that data needed to conclude a contract or to provide the requested services, or that data relating to the fulfilment of a specific legal obligation incumbent on the Controller (for example, the obligations related to keeping accounting and tax records). Failure to communicate this data will prevent a contract from being concluded or a service from being provided.
This data also meets one of the Controller’s legitimate interests which is to share this information with other companies in the "Centro di Firenze per la Moda Italiana" Group (of which Pitti Immagine S.r.l. is a part), due to organisational or coordination needs or to support the Controller’s activities, within the limits of necessity and proportionality regarding the purpose for which the data is sent, also taking into account the nature of the data processed and the relationship with the Data Subject.
TRANSFERRING DATA TO A THIRD COUNTRY
If data is transferred to a third country, the Controller will comply with the provisions of Chapter V of EU Regulation no. 679/2016. Every necessary precaution will be taken in order to ensure that the personal data is protected by basing this transfer on: a) adequacy decisions regarding third countries adopted by the European Commission; b) adequate guarantees given by the third party recipient pursuant to article 46 of the EU Regulation; c) adopting binding corporate rules.
The Controller will also transfer personal data, even in the absence of the aforementioned conditions, if one of the derogation situations exist as provided for by article 49 of the EU Regulation.
You may contact the Controller for more specific information on transfers made to a third country.
COMMUNICATION TO THIRD PARTIES
The data collected may be sent to third parties exclusively for the purposes specified above or to fulfil a connected, instrumental or supporting activity.
These third parties will process the data as independent Controllers or, depending on the case, as External Processors expressly appointed by the Controller. In this latter case, Processors will follow the Controller’s instructions and will be under the Controller’s supervision.
This essentially involves the following categories:
- the Controller's employees, suppliers and collaborators;
- external companies and other professionals who carry out specific services on our behalf;
- a service provider, to send the newsletter, which has been appointed as an external processor;
- Newspapers and the press in general, PRs, Bloggers and Photographers to manage;
- communications and initiatives related to trade shows and other organised events;
- bodies and Public Administrations for compliance with legal requirements.
STORAGE TIMES
A Data Subject's personal data will be kept for the time necessary to fulfil the existing relationships between the parties and to fulfil the relative obligations, without prejudice to storing data for a longer period as may be required by law. Once such a period ends, the data will be erased.
THE DATA SUBJECT’S RIGHTS
In accordance with the law in force, the Data Subject may assert his/her rights vis-à-vis the Controller, as stated by Regulation 679/2016, i.e.:
- Right of access (art. 15);
- Right to rectification (art. 16);
- Right to erasure (art. 17);
- Right to restriction of processing (art. 18);
- Right to data portability (art. 20);
- Right to object (21);
- Right to withdraw consent;
- Right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority in the cases provided for by the Regulation. For more details, consult the Italian Data Protection Authority’s site www.garanteprivacy.it.
To exercise any of the aforementioned rights, the Controller should be contacted at the address indicated above, specifying the subject of the request.
Upon receiving a specific request from a Data Subject, pursuant toarticles 15-22 of the Regulation, the Controller will provide as a response the information relating to the action taken without unjustified delay and, in any case, at the latest within one month from the date on which the request was received.
This deadline may be extended to two months, if necessary, after taking into account the complexity and number of requests received. The Controller will inform the Data Subject of any extension and the reasons for the delay within one month from the date on which the request was received.
In the event that the request is not deemed to be admissible, the Data Subject will be informed, without delay, and, at the latest, within one month from the date on which the request was received, of the reasons for which the request cannot be fulfilled and of the option to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority as well as the option of appealing to a judicial authority.
The Data Subject’s individual rights are detailed below:
RIGHT OF ACCESS – art. 15
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him/her is being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and the following information:
a) the purposes of the processing;
b) the categories of personal data concerned;
c) the recipients or categories of recipient to whom the personal data has been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;
d) where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;
e) the existence of the right to request from the Controller rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the Data Subject or to object to such processing;
f) the right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority;
g) where the personal data is not collected from the Data Subject, any available information as to its source;
h) the existence of automated decision-making processes, including profiling, referred to in article 22(1) and (4) and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for the Data Subject.
1. Where personal data is transferred to a third country or to an international organisation, the Data Subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards pursuant to article 46 relating to the transfer.
2. The Controller shall provide a copy of the personal data undergoing processing. For any further copies requested by the Data Subject, the Controller may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs. Where the Data Subject makes the request by electronic means, and unless otherwise requested by the Data Subject, the information shall be provided in a commonly used electronic form.
The right to obtain a copy shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO RECTIFICATION - art. 16
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him/her. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, the Data Subject shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
RIGHT TO ERASURE - art. 17
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller the erasure of personal data concerning him/her without undue delay and the Controller shall have the obligation to erase personal data without undue delay where one of the following grounds applies:
a) the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise processed;
b) the Data Subject withdraws consent on which the processing is based according to point (a) of article 6(1), or point (a) of article 9(2), and where there is no other legal ground for the processing;
c) the Data Subject objects to the processing pursuant to article 21(1) and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing, or the Data Subject objects to the processing pursuant to article 21(2);
d) the personal data has been unlawfully processed;
e) the personal data has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation in Union or Member State law to which the Controller is subject;
f) the personal data has been collected in relation to the offer of information society services referred to in article 8(1).
2. Where the Controller has made the personal data public and is obliged pursuant to paragraph 1 to erase the personal data, the Controller, taking account of available technology and the cost of implementation, shall take reasonable steps, including technical measures, to inform controllers which are processing the personal data that the Data Subject has requested the erasure by such controllers of any links to, or copy or replication of, those personal data.
3. Paragraphs 1 and 2 shall not apply to the extent that processing is necessary:
a) for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information;
b) for compliance with a legal obligation which requires processing by Union or Member State law to which the Controller is subject or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Controller;
c) for reasons of public interest in the area of public health in accordance with points (h) and (i) of article 9(2) as well as article 9(3);
d) for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes in accordance with article 89(1) in so far as the right referred to in paragraph 1 is likely to render impossible or seriously impair the achievement of the objectives of that processing; or
e) to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law.
RIGHT TO RESTRICTION OF PROCESSING - art. 18
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies:
a) the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the Data Subject, for a period enabling the Controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data;
b) the processing is unlawful and the Data Subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests the restriction of their use instead;
c) the Controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but the data is required by the Data Subject to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law;
d) the Data Subject has objected to processing pursuant to article 21(1) pending the verification of whether the legitimate grounds of the Controller override those of the Data Subject.
2. Where processing has been restricted under paragraph 1, such personal data shall, with the exception of storage, only be processed with the Data Subject's consent or to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law or to protect the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest of the Union or of a Member State.
3. A Data Subject who has obtained restriction of processing pursuant to paragraph 1 shall be informed by the Controller before the restriction of processing is lifted.
RIGHT TO DATA PORTABILITY – art. 20
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to receive the personal data concerning him/her, which he/she has provided to a Controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and shall have the right to transmit that data to another controller without hindrance from the Controller to which the personal data has been provided, where:
a) the processing is based on consent pursuant to point (a) of article 6(1) or point (a) of article 9(2) or on a contract pursuant to point (b) of article 6(1); and
b) the processing is carried out by automated means.
2. In exercising his/her right to data portability pursuant to paragraph 1, the Data Subject shall have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible.
3. The exercise of the right referred to in paragraph 1 of this article shall be without prejudice to article 17. That right shall not apply to processing necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Controller.
4. The right referred to in paragraph 1 shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO OBJECT - art. 21
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to his/her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning him/her which is based on point (e) or (f) of article 6(1), including profiling based on those provisions. The Controller shall no longer process the personal data unless the Controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the Data Subject or to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law.
2. Where personal data is processed for direct marketing purposes, the Data Subject shall have the right to object at any time to the processing of the personal data concerning him/her for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.
3. Where the Data Subject objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the personal data shall no longer be processed for such purposes.
4. At the latest at the time of the first communication with the Data Subject, the right referred to in paragraphs 1 and 2 shall be explicitly brought to the attention of the Data Subject and shall be presented clearly and separately from any other information.
5. In the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, the Data Subject may exercise his/her right to object by automated means using technical specifications.
6. Where personal data is processed for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes pursuant to article 89(1), the Data Subject, on grounds relating to his/her particular situation, shall have the right to object to the processing of the personal data concerning him/her, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
NEWSLETTER SERVICE
If you do not wish to receive our newsletter, you may unsubscribe at any moment by clicking the "Unsubscribe" link found in any of the emails received from us.
In the event of a technical problem, you may notify us by email at the address given above.
PRESS INFORMATION NOTICE
Pursuant to the new Regulation 679/2016, in accordance with the principle of accountability, any processing of personal data shall be lawful, fair and transparent. Specifically, this means that processing will be done in respect of the principles of lawfulness, fairness, correctness, proportionality, necessity, accuracy, completeness and security, and that the Data Subject is advised of the existence of the processing, its purposes and the rights which the Data Subject can exercise.
With this in mind, we provide below the necessary information regarding the processing that we normally carry out and the rights you have under current privacy legislation.
In general, we do not carry out processing of any particular relevance with specific regard to natural persons. We do not collect a lot of data and what we do collect is restricted to personal details, company names, email addresses or telephone numbers, or, essentially, that data needed to fulfil contractual obligations and connected to the legal obligations incumbent on our company, or that data which we process on the basis of our legitimate interests in carrying out our business in compliance with practices in the sector in which we operate and in proportion to that which is normally expected within the scope of professionalism.
When necessary, as part of carrying out an Event or an initiative connected to one, we may provide you with additional information in relation to any further processing which may be done, which is understood as being supplementary to or even just a specification of this information notice.
We invite you to read this information carefully and we remain available should you have any queries or require further information regarding how we process and how we safeguard your personal data.
Information notice concerning the protection of personal data pursuant to article 12 et seq. of EU regulation 679/2016
CONTROLLER - CONTACT DETAILS
PITTI IMMAGINE S.r.l., with offices in Via Faenza, 111 – Florence, Italy, in the person of the legal representative pro-tempore, is the Controller in terms of processing personal data pursuant to and for the effects of EU Regulation 2016/679.
For any communication regarding privacy or to exercise a right due to a Data Subject under current legislation, the Controller has made this email address available: privacy@pittimmagine.com.
CATEGORIES OF DATA – PROCESSING SYSTEMS
The personal data we process is that data requested on the “My Pitti” computer registration system on the institutional site.
Generally speaking, we ask for personal details,company names, email addresses or telephone numbers.
he personal data provided on the registration form is also stored in a badge that we deliver to you in order to allow you to access the trade show.
We may also receive from you - and consequently process - certain personal data relative to parties who, for various reasons, collaborate with you, such as personal details, contact details, (email, telephone number, etc.), as well as other common personal data which is needed in order to fulfil the professional relationship with our company. It should be noted that - in this regard - it is your responsibility to divulge the contents of this information notice to those parties whose data, for various reasons, is sent as part of the relationship with our company.
PROCESSING METHODS AND CONFIDENTIALITY OBLIGATION
Data is processed by means of IT tools and/or manually on paper, by persons expressly authorised by the Controller or, in any case, by persons bound by confidentiality agreements, using logic appropriate to the purposes for which the data was collected and, in any case, in order to guarantee the security and confidentiality of the data.
The data collected will not be disclosed or disseminated to third parties pursuant to the law.
THE PURPOSE OF THE PROCESSING - LEGAL BASIS
Personal data collected will be used for the purposes connected to your profession of Journalist, PR, Blogger, Photographer, Guest, in order to notify you of our events, trade shows, exhibitions and any other of our initiatives in general.
The personal data processed does not require your consent.
In fact, processing your data is necessary in order to pursue our legitimate interests in notifying you about our initiatives, taking account of your profession.
Within the limits of this purpose, we use the personal data which you have provided us as part of the registration process in our system as well as to send you our periodic Newsletter, without prejudice to your right to object to receiving the same, either from the outset or at any moment thereafter and without formality.
PROVIDING DATA
Communicating personal data - as part of the registration process given above - is essential in order to be able to contact you and to fulfil the relationship for the purposes and with the methods detailed above.
TRANSFERRING DATA TO A THIRD COUNTRY
If data is transferred to a third country, the Controller will comply with the provisions of Chapter V of EU Regulation no. 679/2016. Every necessary precaution will be taken in order to ensure that the personal data is protected by basing this transfer on: a) adequacy decisions regarding third countries adopted by the European Commission; b) adequate guarantees given by the third party recipient pursuant to article 46 of the EU Regulation; c) adopting binding corporate rules.
The Controller will also transfer personal data, even in the absence of the aforementioned conditions, if one of the derogation situations exist as provided for by article 49 of the EU Regulation.
You may contact the Controller for more specific information on transfers made to a third country.
COMMUNICATION TO THIRD PARTIES
The data collected may be sent to third parties exclusively for the purposes specified above or to fulfil a connected, instrumental or supporting activity.
These third parties will process the data as independent Controllers or, depending on the case, as External Processors expressly appointed by the Controller. In this latter case, Processors will follow the Controller’s instructions and will be under the Controller’s supervision.
This essentially involves the following categories:
the Controller's employees, suppliers and collaborators;
external companies and other professionals who carry out specific services on our behalf;
a service provider, to send the newsletter, which has been appointed as an external processor;
bodies and Public Administrations for compliance with legal requirements.
The access badge which we deliver contains personal data that you provided us with in the registration form. Exhibitors are able to read this badge through an optical reader and this allows them access to the personal data contained in this form, in compliance with the purposes and the processing methods each one employs.
This data also meets one of the Controller’s legitimate interests which is to share this information with other companies in the "Centro di Firenze per la Moda Italiana" Group (of which Pitti Immagine S.r.l. is a part), due to organisational or coordination needs or to support the Controller’s activities, within the limits of necessity and proportionality regarding the purpose for which the data is sent, also taking into account the nature of the data processed and the relationship with the Data Subject.
STORAGE TIMES
A Data Subject's personal data will be kept for the time necessary to fulfil the existing relationships between the parties and to fulfil the relative obligations, without prejudice to storing data for a longer period as may be required by law. Once such a period ends, the data will be erased.
If a request is made to unsubscribe from our mailing list, we will erase your personal data immediately.
THE DATA SUBJECT’S RIGHTS
In accordance with the law in force, the Data Subject may assert his/her rights vis-à-vis the Controller, as stated by Regulation 679/2016, i.e.:
- Right of access (art. 15);
- Right to rectification (art. 16);
- Right to erasure (art. 17);
- Right to restriction of processing (art. 18);
- Right to data portability (art. 20);
- Right to object (21);
- Right to withdraw consent;
- Right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority in the cases provided for by the Regulation. For more details, consult the Italian Data Protection Authority’s site www.garanteprivacy.it.
To exercise any of the aforementioned rights, the Controller should be contacted at the address indicated above, specifying the subject of the request.
Upon receiving a specific request from a Data Subject, pursuant to articles 15-22 of the Regulation, the Controller will provide as a response the information relating to the action taken without unjustified delay and, in any case, at the latest within one month from the date on which the request was received.
This deadline may be extended to two months, if necessary, after taking into account the complexity and number of requests received. The Controller will inform the Data Subject of any extension and the reasons for the delay within one month from the date on which the request was received.
In the event that the request is not deemed to be admissible, the Data Subject will be informed, without delay, and, at the latest, within one month from the date on which the request was received, of the reasons for which the request cannot be fulfilled and of the option to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority as well as the option of appealing to a judicial authority.
The Data Subject’s individual rights are detailed below:
RIGHT OF ACCESS – art. 15
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him/her is being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and the following information:
a) the purposes of the processing;
b) the categories of personal data concerned;
c) the recipients or categories of recipient to whom the personal data has been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;
d) where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;
e) the existence of the right to request from the Controller rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the Data Subject or to object to such processing;
f) the right to lodge a complaint with a Supervisory Authority;
g) where the personal data is not collected from the Data Subject, any available information as to its source;
h) the existence of automated decision-making processes, including profiling, referred to in article 22(1) and (4) and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for the Data Subject.
1. Where personal data is transferred to a third country or to an international organisation, the Data Subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards pursuant to article 46 relating to the transfer.
2. The Controller shall provide a copy of the personal data undergoing processing. For any further copies requested by the Data Subject, the Controller may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs. Where the Data Subject makes the request by electronic means, and unless otherwise requested by the Data Subject, the information shall be provided in a commonly used electronic form.
The right to obtain a copy shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO RECTIFICATION - art. 16
The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him/her. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, the Data Subject shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
RIGHT TO ERASURE - art. 17
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller the erasure of personal data concerning him/her without undue delay and the Controller shall have the obligation to erase personal data without undue delay where one of the following grounds applies:
a) the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise processed;
b) the Data Subject withdraws consent on which the processing is based according to point (a) of article 6(1), or point (a) of article 9(2), and where there is no other legal ground for the processing;
c) the Data Subject objects to the processing pursuant to article 21(1) and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing, or the Data Subject objects to the processing pursuant to article 21(2);
d) the personal data has been unlawfully processed;
e) the personal data has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation in Union or Member State law to which the Controller is subject;
f) the personal data has been collected in relation to the offer of information society services referred to in article 8(1).
2. Where the Controller has made the personal data public and is obliged pursuant to paragraph 1 to erase the personal data, the Controller, taking account of available technology and the cost of implementation, shall take reasonable steps, including technical measures, to inform controllers which are processing the personal data that the Data Subject has requested the erasure by such controllers of any links to, or copy or replication of, those personal data.
3. Paragraphs 1 and 2 shall not apply to the extent that processing is necessary:
a) for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information;
b) for compliance with a legal obligation which requires processing by Union or Member State law to which the Controller is subject or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Controller;
c) for reasons of public interest in the area of public health in accordance with points (h) and (i) of article 9(2) as well as article 9(3);
d) for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes in accordance with article 89(1) in so far as the right referred to in paragraph 1 is likely to render impossible or seriously impair the achievement of the objectives of that processing; or
e) to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law.
RIGHT TO RESTRICTION OF PROCESSING - art. 18
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to obtain from the Controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies:
a) the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the Data Subject, for a period enabling the Controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data;
b) the processing is unlawful and the Data Subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests the restriction of their use instead;
c) the Controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but the data is required by the Data Subject to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law;
d) the Data Subject has objected to processing pursuant to article 21(1) pending the verification of whether the legitimate grounds of the Controller override those of the Data Subject.
2. Where processing has been restricted under paragraph 1, such personal data shall, with the exception of storage, only be processed with the Data Subject's consent or to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law or to protect the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest of the Union or of a Member State.
3. A Data Subject who has obtained restriction of processing pursuant to paragraph 1 shall be informed by the Controller before the restriction of processing is lifted.
RIGHT TO DATA PORTABILITY – art. 20
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to receive the personal data concerning him/her, which he/she has provided to a Controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and shall have the right to transmit that data to another controller without hindrance from the Controller to which the personal data has been provided, where:
a) the processing is based on consent pursuant to point (a) of article 6(1) or point (a) of article 9(2) or on a contract pursuant to point (b) of article 6(1); and
b) the processing is carried out by automated means.
2. In exercising his/her right to data portability pursuant to paragraph 1, the Data Subject shall have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible.
3. The exercise of the right referred to in paragraph 1 of this article shall be without prejudice to article 17. That right shall not apply to processing necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Controller.
4. The right referred to in paragraph 1 shall not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
RIGHT TO OBJECT TO PROCESSING – art. 21
1. The Data Subject shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to his/her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning him/her which is based on point (e) or (f) of article 6(1), including profiling based on those provisions. The Controller shall no longer process the personal data unless the Controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the Data Subject or to establish, exercise or defend a right in a court of law.
2. Where personal data is processed for direct marketing purposes, the Data Subject shall have the right to object at any time to the processing of the personal data concerning him/her for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.
3. Where the Data Subject objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the personal data shall no longer be processed for such purposes.
4. At the latest at the time of the first communication with the Data Subject, the right referred to in paragraphs 1 and 2 shall be explicitly brought to the attention of the Data Subject and shall be presented clearly and separately from any other information.
5. In the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, the Data Subject may exercise his/her right to object by automated means using technical specifications.
6. Where personal data is processed for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes pursuant to article 89(1), the Data Subject, on grounds relating to his/her particular situation, shall have the right to object to the processing of the personal data concerning him/her, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
NEWSLETTER SERVICE
If you do not wish to receive our newsletter, you may unsubscribe at any moment by clicking the "Unsubscribe" link found in any of the emails received from us.
In the event of a technical problem, you may notify us by email at the address given above.
